What the...?
怎么回...？
Ah... no... no! No!
啊...不...不！不要！
Day of the Daleks
(Whopix fan edit)
Dalek 之日
(粉丝剪辑版)
(基于 opensubtitles.org 字幕)
(Sincro: wyxchari)
(翻译/时间轴: 巴蛮子sz)
Doctor, why don't you take a break?
博士，你为什么不休息一下？
It's maddening, you know. So nearly there.
很让人抓狂啊，知道吧。感觉很接近了
If I could only cut out their override
on the dematerialisation circuit.
只要我能切断他们的优先控制权就好了，他们锁住了反物质化电路
Let me see those figures.
让我看看那些图纸
Doctor?
博士？
I thought the TARDIS was working again.
我以为 TARDIS 又可以用了
What gave you that idea?
谁给了你这样的想法？
Oh, being dragged off to an alien planet
five hundred years in the future, for example.
哦，比如说，我被拖到了五百年后的一颗外星
Oh, you know - all that business
with the miners and the colonists.
你知道的，都是矿工啊殖民者啊那些事
My dear Jo, the TARDIS was being operated then
under remote control by the High Council of the Time Lords.
亲爱的 Jo, TARDIS 那时候是被时间领主最高议会远程控制着呢
Well, if it worked for them...
如果对他们来说这可以用...
I don't want it to work for them.
I want it to work for me.
我不想它对他们可以用，我想要它对我可以用
No-one's going to turn me into
an interplanetary puppet.
任何人别想把我变成一个星际傀儡
Yes, of course. Why didn't I think of that before?
啊，是了，我之前怎么没有想到过？
Yes, of course. I remember now.
是的，当然，我想起来了
Look, don't worry, my dear.
I know you're alarmed but you needn't be.
看，别担心，亲爱的。我知道你受惊了，但没有必要
Yes, well I think that should do it.
Why on Earth I never realised that...
是的，我想这应该可以了。为什么我从来没有意识到...
Oh no! What are you doing here?
噢！你在这里做什么？
Well, I'm not here. Don't worry.
其实，我没在这里。别担心
Well, that is, in a sense, er, I am here,
but, erm, you are not there.
不过，其实是，某种程度上，我在这里，但是，呃，你不在那里
Er... yes, well, it's a bit difficult
to explain really.
呃...这个，的确有点难解释
This won't do at all!
We can't have two of us running about.
完全说不通！不可能有两个我在这里乱转！
Yes, well don't worry. It will all sor...
是的，不过不用担心。一切都会弄清...
Doctor! What happened?
博士！发生了什么？
Well, it's a very complicated thing - time - Jo.
这个, 它是一件很复杂的事情 - 时间 - Jo
Once you've begun tampering with it,
the oddest things start happening.
一旦你开始玩弄它，奇怪的事情就会出现
But there was another you and another... me.
但刚才有另一个你和另一个...我
Well, where've they gone?
他们都去哪儿了？
Back into their own time stream, of course.
Or do I mean forward?
当然是退回到他们自己的时间流去了，或者不是退回是前进？
But, Doctor, I don't understand...
但是，博士，我搞不明白...
Look, Jo. Don't worry about it. It was a freak affect.
It's very unlikely to happen again.
听着, Jo, 别担心。这是一个奇怪的现象，非常不可能再次发生
Hold that and give me those papers.
拿着这个，把纸夹给我
Ah, Doctor. Glad you're still here.
啊，博士，很高兴你还在这里
I need your help.
我需要你的帮助
Sorry, Brigadier. I'm busy.
对不起，准将，我正忙
Yeah, so am I, Doctor, so am I. /?
是，我也是，博士，我也是
Now then, you've heard of Sir Reginald Styles?
现在看看，你听说过 Reginald Styles 爵士吧？
No, can't say that I have.
没，不能说我听过
Well isn't he the chief representative at the UN?
但他不是驻联合国首席代表吗？
That's right - key figure at the latest
summit conference.
正是 - 是最近的峰会上的关键人物
My dear chap, I'm a scientist. Not a politician.
我亲爱的小伙，我是个科学家，不是个政客
You know, Doctor, if you... didn't spend so much time.../?
知道吗，博士，如果你...没有花那么多时间...
...tinkering around with this wretched contraption,
...摆弄这个可怜的装置的话
you'd realise just how bad
the international situation's become.
你就会意识到国际形势变得多么糟糕
Humans are always squabbling over something, Brigadier.
人类总是会为点什么事争论不休, 准将
Yes, well, this particular squabble looks like
ending up in a third world war.
是的, 好吧, 这一次的争吵看起来像是要导致第三次世界大战似的
The Chinese delegation have refused to attend.
Without them, the conference can't even begin.
中国代表团拒绝出席。没有他们, 会议甚至无法开始
Now Styles is flying to Peking in a few hours./?
现在 Styles 几个小时后就要飞往北京
There's just a chance that he can
persuade them to change their minds.
他也许有机会说服他们改变主意
All right, Brigadier. So what's his problem?
好吧, 准将。那他那里有什么问题？
Well, he was working late last night,
down at Auderly...
他昨晚在 Auderly 工作到很晚...
Where's that?
Auderly 是什么地方？
Auderly, Miss Grant, is a Government owned
country house about fifty miles north of London/?
Auderly 是政府拥有的一栋乡村房子，在伦敦北面大约50英里
- where the conference is due to be held.
- Oh.
- 和平会议将在那里进行  - 哦
He suddenly started behaving... rather oddly./?
他突然开始表现得...相当奇怪
Seemed to think that someone
was trying to assassinate him.
似乎是觉得有人试图暗杀他
Any idea who?
知道是谁吗？
Some sort of "ghost" apparently.
看起来像是是某种 "鬼"
He said somebody attacked him and vanished.
他说有人袭击了他，然后就消失了
And you're absolutely certain that
he used the word "ghost"?
你完全确定他用了 "鬼" 这个词吗？
Oh yes. But afterwards he...
嗯是的，但随后他...
Miss Paget! What's going on here?!
Paget 小姐！这是在干什么？
These people are from UNIT, sir.
这些人来自 UNIT，先生
Who asked them to come here?
谁让他们来这里的？
I did - because of what happened yesterday.
我让的 - 因为昨晚发生的事情
Nothing happened yesterday.
昨晚没发生什么事
There seems to have been
some sort of incident, Sir Reginald?
似乎是发生了某种意外，Reginald 爵士？
Nothing of any importance.
没有什么重要的事
Well, if you could tell us what happened?
那，你可以告诉我们到底发生了什么吗？
I was working late. I must have dropped off.
我工作到很晚，然后肯定是睡着了
Freak gust of wind, blew some papers off my desk,
可怕的大风把我桌子上的一些文件吹掉了
I woke up rather confused,
I was picking up the papers /?
我迷迷糊糊地醒过来，开始捡那些文件
- when Miss Paget came in.
- But you did mention ghosts.
- 这个时候 Paget 小姐进来的  - 但你的确之前提到过“鬼魂”
Did I? Must have been having a nightmare.
有吗？我肯定是做了噩梦了
But the French windows weren't shut.
I closed them before I went to bed.
但落地窗没有关闭。我在上床之前是关了的
Then I must have opened them!
那肯定是我打开了它们！
Did you, er, did you also make
those marks on the floor over there?
是你, 呃, 是你在那边地板上留下了那些痕迹吗？
Muddy feet, Sir Reginald.
Someone was in here, you know.
泥脚印, Reginald 爵士。昨晚有人在这里, 你知道的
Are you accusing me of lying, sir?!
你是在指控我撒谎啰, 先生?!
Sir Reginald, you've obviously been
under considerable strain recently.
Reginald 爵士, 最近这段时间你的压力显然很大
Were you feeling at all unwell last night?
你昨晚没有不舒服的感觉吧？
I felt, and feel, perfectly well.
我昨晚和现在都感觉非常好
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've a lot to do.
I'm due at the airport in an hour.
现在, 请原谅, 我还有好多事情要做。一小时内要到机场
You've no objection to my men
searching the grounds?
你不反对我的人把这里搜查一遍吧？
None at all. Though I really don't know
what you hope to find.
完全不。虽然我真的不知道你想要找到什么
Sergeant!
中士！
Ah, he's in a bad way, poor chap.
You'd better get him to the hospital.
啊, 他情况不好, 可怜的家伙, 你最好把他送医院去
- Captain Yates...  - Right away, sir.
- Yates 队长...  - 马上, 先生
This is a new one on me.
What do you make of it, Doctor?
这我都没见过。你对它有什么想法，博士？
I'm not sure...
我不确定...
Sir?
头儿？
What've you got there, Benton?
你找到了什么，Benton？
No idea, sir.
不知道，头儿
It was hidden about fifty feet inside the tunnel.
它被藏在隧道里面50英尺的位置
Have you seen this before?
你以前见过这个吗？
Really Brigadier!
What sort of games are you playing?
真的吗, 准将！你到底在玩什么游戏？
It's not a game, sir.
It's our duty to protect you!
这不是游戏, 先生。我们有责任保护你！
I don't need your protection!
我不需要你们的保护！
Sir Reginald, we've just found a very severely
injured man down by the canal tunnel.
Reginald 爵士, 我们在运河隧道边发现一个严重受伤的人
Oh really? And what did he look like?
哦真的吗？他什么样子？
Thirty-fiveish, average build. He was wearing
a sort of guerilla combat suit.
大约25岁, 中等身材, 穿着一种迷彩作战服
- And carrying that gun.
- I am very sorry, gentlemen,
- 还带着枪  - 我很抱歉, 先生们
but I have rather more important things
on my mind at the moment.
但我这会儿想起还有更加重要的事情
- If you'll excuse me?
- I've arranged an escort to take you to the airport, sir.
- 抱歉呢  - 我安排几个人护送你到机场去, 爵士
Thank you, but it shouldn't be necessary.
谢谢你, 但这并没有必要
I'm sorry, sir, but I think it will!
抱歉, 爵士, 但我觉得有必要
Oh, if you insist.
哦, 你非得坚持
I'd like to get that gun down to the laboratory
and run a few tests on it.
我得把那把枪拿到实验室去做几个测试
Well, basically it's a form of ultra-sonic disintegrator.
好了, 基本上来说它是一种超声裂解枪
You mean a ray gun?
你是说射线枪？
That's right, Jo, I mean a ray gun.
说对了, Jo, 我的意思是射线枪
Only it's far more sophisticated than any weapon
yet invented on Earth. Now take a look at this.
只不过它比地球上说造的任何武器都复杂, 现在看着
Quite an effective little weapon, eh?
非常厉害的小武器, 是哈？
Doctor, you say this wasn't made on Earth.
Do you mean it comes from another planet?
博士, 你说它不是在地球上造的, 那就是说它来自其它星球？
Well that was my theory at first, yes.
这也是我一开始的想法, 是
But the metallurgical analysis shows that the,
er, iron constituent is very much of this world.
但是材料分析却表明, 它的钢铁成分是属于这个世界的
In fact, it was mined not very far from here
- North Wales.
事实上, 就来自离这里不远的地方 - 北威尔士
How do you explain that?
那你怎么解释？
Do you believe in ghosts, Brigadier?
你相信鬼魂吗, 准将？
Let's be serious, Doctor.
我们说正经的了, 博士
I am.
我很正经
Oh, come along, Doctor, come along.
哦, 得了, 博士, 拉倒吧
Oh, my mistake. I was forgetting
the unimaginative nature of the military mind.
哦, 我错了, 我忘记了一个军人的大脑是没有想象力的
But we saw a couple of "Amicus Seperatus"
a few moments ago, didn't we, Jo?
当我们在不久之前见到 Amicus Seperatus 现象了, 对不, Jo?
Did we?
有吗？
Yes, here in this laboratory.
是的, 就在这实验室
Oh, you mean when we...
哦, 你是说我们那时...
Mind you, they were manifestations
of a much more benevolent kind.
fixme
None of your clanking chains and chilly fingers!
But ghosts, none the less.
That was because you were playing around
with the time mechanism on the TARDIS, wasn't it?
那是因为你当时在折腾 TARDIS 的时间机制, 是吧？
Still can't get it to work, eh?
还是没法让它工作啊, 嗯？
Well, I can't get this thing to work, either.
是啊, 我也不能让它工作
But this is a form of, er, of time machine
of a very crude kind.
但这是一个, 呃, 时间机器, 比较粗糙的那种
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Come over here. Look at this.
到这里来, 看看这个
Now what do you think that is?
你觉得这是什么？
Ooh, it's a... mini-dematerialisation circuit.
哦, 这是个...迷你型的反物质化电路
Top of the class, Jo.
Now then, pop this in here, like that.
优等生, Jo。既然如此, 把这个塞到这里, 这样
Now, as far as I can gather,
when you push this button, it should...
现在, 据我的推断, 一旦你按下这个按钮, 它就可以...
Good grief! It's working!
老天爷, 它可以工作了！
Sir?
头儿？
What is it?
什么事？
Time transmitter in operation, sir.
Twentieth Century Zone.
时间发射器在运转了, 头儿, 在20世纪区域
Can you fix the space-time coordinates?
你能锁定时空坐标吗？
Do be careful, Doctor!
小心点, 博士！
All right, Jo, all right.
没事的, Jo, 没事
- Well?  - No good, sir.
- 怎样  - 不行, 头儿
There was a transference, I think,
but the machine's cut out completely.
刚才有干扰, 我觉得, 然后机器就完全切断了
Continue scanning - and next time
you had better be more efficient!
继续扫描 - 下次你最好效率高点
Report!
报告！
Yes, I see. All right, sergeant.
You'd better report back to Captain Yates. Goodbye.
是的, 我明白, 没事, 中士。你最好报告给 Yates 队长, 再见
That was Benton. He was in the ambulance
with the man we found.
Benton, 他刚才跟我们找到的那个人一起在救护车上
Well?
怎么了？
Well according to him, that man just...
vanished, faded away
据他所说, 那个人刚刚...消失了, 慢慢淡出了
- like a ghost.  - Oh no!
- 像鬼一样  - 噢, 不！
Well, Doctor, what now?
那, 博士, 现在怎么办？
Well, everything that happens seems to
centre round Styles' house.
嗯, 发生的所有这些事似乎都是跟 Style 的房子有关的
Obviously.
这显然
And whoever tried to harm him
will probably try again.
那些试图伤害他的人, 很可能还会再次下手
Jo, how would you like to spend the night
in a haunted house?
Jo, 你觉得到闹鬼的房子里过一晚怎么样？
Wake up, Jo.
醒醒, Jo
It's all right. It's morning.
没什么事, 天亮了
Nothing's happened?
什么都没发生？
No, nothing at all.
没有, 完全没有
Jo! Jo!
Please! Turn that machine off
- or they'll kill all of us! Please!
拜托, 把那个机器关掉 - 不然他们会把我们都杀死！求你了
Sir?
头儿？
Yes?
怎么？
We've picked up that time transmitter again.
我们又识别到那个时间发射器了
You're sure?
你确定吗？
Yes, sir. Same frequency, same time...
time zone. Much stronger now.
是的, 头儿。同样的频率同样的时间..时区。现在信号强多了
Right. I want the exact space-time co-ordinates,
so whatever happens, don't lose it!
好, 我要确切的时空坐标, 所有不管发生什么, 不要跟丢了
What is your report?
你要报告什么？
We have a fix on the time transfer device.
我们已经锁定了那个时间传送装置
It is operating again in the twentieth century
time zone and it must be them.
它在20世纪区域再次开启, 肯定是他们
You have obtained the space-time co-ordinates?
你已经得到了时空坐标？
We're trying now. The trace is
much stronger this time.
我们正在尝试, 这次信号比较强
- There is every chance...
- You must not fail!
- 这次肯定有机会...  - 你必须成功！
Security forces are standing by.
安全部队已经在待命了
If we do get the co-ordinates,
what are your instructions?
如果我们拿到坐标, 你们有什么指示？
Whoever is operating the time machine
is an enemy of the Daleks.
不管是谁在操作那个时间机器, 他都是 Daleks 的敌人
All enemies of the Daleks must be destroyed!
Exterminate them!
而 Daleks 的所有敌人都必须消灭！终结他们！